Ayush Agrawal

AI Researcher



(+91) 6265570432



ayush8120.github.io



ay.agrawal812@gmail.com



Ayush8120

Overview -

Research Interests

Foundation Models | Computer Vision Reinforcement Learning **Embodied AI Graph Neural Networks** HCI

Skills

C/C++ Python MATLAB LaTeX OpenCV Git Pytorch Tensorflow ROS

Coursework

Probability & Statistics

Linear Algebra Image Processing

Discrete Mathematics

Neural Networks & Fuzzy Logic

Object Oriented Programming

Online Courses:

RL-By David Silver

Deep Learning Specialization

Education -

BE Electronics & Instrumentation Engineering

BITS Pilani

2018 - 2022 | Pilani, India

References-

Dr. Krishna Murthy: MIT Dr. K Madhava Krishna: IIIT-H **Dr. Brojeshwar Bhowmick: ■** *TCS*

Research Experience

May 2022 -Present

Research Assistant (*) Robotics Research Center, IIIT Hyderabad Tags: Embodied AI, RL, Graph Neural Networks, Foundational Models Supervisor: Dr. K Madhava Krishna, Dr. Mohan Sridharan, Dr. Krishna Murthy

- · Collaborating with TCS Research, Kolkata, India to enhance the performance of embodied agents in object navigation, multi-object navigation, and household tidying-up tasks.
- Proposed Sequence Agnostic Multi-Object Navigation (SAM) task, wherein the agent is neither provided nor forced to compute a global order in which it locates instances of the target objects.
- Proposed a GCN encoder leveraging Foundation Models for generating object-room co-occurrence affinities that align well with Human CommonSense (CLIPGraphs)
- · Currently working on a framework, where, an embodied agent must tidy a house by rearranging misplaced objects using scene graphs and CLIPGraphs Affinities

Nov 2021 -May 2022

Research Intern 🚨 🖻

Bio-Engineering Lab, UNSW Canberra

Tags: Bio-Inspired DL, Sequential Modelling

Supervisor: Dr. Sridhar Ravi

- Worked on my undergraduate thesis on the topic: Obstacle Avoidance in drones Using Bee Vision inspired Algorithms
- · Implemented Deep Learning techniques to model the relationship between Geometric Optic Flow and Obstacle Avoidance in Bees, curated real honeybee trajectory dataset, and proposed an LSTM+CNNs model achieving 75% accuracy.
- · Successfully tested the model in custom tunnels with multiple obstacles, resulting in avoiding obstacles each time.

June 2021 - Research Intern 🗘

ARMS Lab, IIT Bombay

August 2021 Tags: Decentralized Algorithms Supervisor: Dr. Arpita Sinha

- · Successfully implemented a Decentralized Multi-Drone Terrain Exploration algorithm on ROS and Gazebo using PX4 drones, ensuring complete exploration in a limited number of steps
- Utilized an incidence matrix as a mode of communication between robots and vertex, eliminating the need for inter-robot communica-

Publications

A. Agrawal, A. Datta, N. Gireesh, S. Banerjee, M. Sridharan, B. Bhowmick, and M. Krishna, Sequence-Agnostic Multi-Object Navigation in IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation(ICRA), 2023, (to be published).

A. Agrawal, R. Arora, A. Datta, S. Banerjee, B. Bhowmick, J.K. Murthy, M. Sridharan, and M. Krishna, CLIPGraphs: Multimodal Graph Networks to Infer Object-Room Affinities in IEEE International Conference On Robot And Human Interactive Communication(RO-MAN), 2023 (Under Review). #

Patents

A. Agrawal, A. Datta, N. Gireesh, S. Banerjee, M. Sridharan, B. Bhowmick, and M. Krishna, Method And System For Multi-Object Tracking And Navigation Without **Pre-Sequencing**, (Patent Pending)

Honors & Awards

· Awarded a INR 50,000 grant by AUGSD BITS Pilani to implement Autonomous Odor Drone